OLIVIA HYLAND

Website: https://www.oliviahyland.ie
Email: 10liviahyland@gmail.com
Contact number: 087 - 654 0814

PERSONAL PROFILE

A highly-motivated, creative and organized individual who has a 2:1 Honors Degree in Fine Art. I have a commitment to continuously learning and a willingness to work hard in any job I apply myself to. I have gained excellent interpersonal and communication skills through my various work experience including work in the UK and USA.

KEY SKILLS

Team-work
 Customer service
 Attention to detail

Communication
 Creative thinking
 Time management

WORK EXPERIENCE

The Laurels Guest House, Kilkenny

Oct 2016- Sept 2019

Front of House/Management

- Experience with the use of property management systems including Booking.com and Little Hotelier
- Ensuring the highest standard of customer service by being attentive to the guests every need
- Responsible for daily administration work i.e. replying to guest mail, front desk, answering phones, taking bookings, online marketing.
- Responsible for setting rates to ensure optimal capacity and profit against competition
- Servicing rooms and ensuring standards are met for customer service, quality, safety and sanitation daily.
- Responsible for dealing with customer complaints and conflict resolution from time to time

Cath Kidston, Grafton Street, Dublin

Oct 2018- Jan 2019

Sales Assistant

- Always ensuring the highest standard of customer service by always being attentive and continually keeping up to date with the latest products and prints
- Praised by management for my ability to work well within a team, displaying good communication skills
- Responsible for processing cash and card payments in a professional and timely manner
- Responsible for the Visual merchandising of the shop window display and in-store floor

BJR Services, Kilkenny - St. Patrick's Special Needs Residential Centre

2015-2018

Household staff

- Attention to detail and meticulous use of proper safety procedures in order to ensure the highest standards of health and safety
- Ability to efficiently manage my time and work one's own initiative

Explore Learning, 1 Merton High St, London SW19 1DD, UK

May-Aug 2011

Tutor

- Guidance and tuition in Mathematics and English in preparation for their SATs and other entrance exams
- Supervising up the 10 children at a time aged between 6-12 years
- Displayed attributes of creativity and patience in order to create a safe, positive, and productive learning environment for the students

Planet Hollywood, 2915 Hollywood Dr, Myrtle Beach, SC 29577, USA

May-Aug 2013

Waiting Staff

- Provided excellent wait service to ensure satisfaction to each customer
- Taking customer orders and delivering food and drinks in a professional and timely manner
- Handling money and billing in a professional and timely manner

Kilford Arms Hotel, John St, Kilkenny

2011-13

Housekeeper

- 50 bedroom fast-paced Hotel within Kilkenny City
- Attention to detail to ensure bedrooms were always cleaned to the highest standard
- Self-directed and motivated in order to ensure rooms were completed and ready on time

EDUCATION

Dun Laoghaire Institute of Art, Design and Technology-IADT

Sept 2011-Jun 2018

2:1 BA Hons in ART Level 8

• I developed my final year project with the use of photography and creative technologies including Adobe Photoshop and Final Cut Pro X. This resulted in video piece which was completed and displayed to exhibition standard. The work was exhibited at The Sculpture in Context Exhibition at the Botanic Gardens in 2018 and subsequently acquired by a Dublin city centre art collector.

Ormonde College of Further Education

Sept 2010- May 2011

FETAC Level 5 certificate in Fine Art - Portfolio Preparation

• I gained work experience at Photography studio Maria of Kilkenny and had experience working in an art teaching position at Presentation Secondary School, Kilkenny where I received excellent feedback overall

Presentation Secondary School, Kilkenny

Sept 2004-Jun 2010

Leaving Certificate. English, Irish, Mathematics, Spanish, Biology, Geography, Art, Home Economics

- During transition year, I had the opportunity to gain work experience at a primary school. I assisted the teacher in the junior and senior infants' classroom with children aged between 4 and 6
- I also had the opportunity to work alongside nurses and care staff at a learning disability residential center and special needs school. Receiving excellent feedback

COURSES & ACHIEVEMENTS

- Junior Certificate Home Economics Outstanding Achievement Award
- Junior Certificate Arts & Crafts Outstanding Achievement Award
- Educational Computers Driver Licence (ECDL) course
- Mentored a team in 6th year for incoming First Years (Le Chéile)

COMPUTER EXPERIENCE

- Proficient with Microsoft Word, Excel, and PowerPoint
- Intermediate knowledge of Front-end programming languages HTML and CSS. Currently learning javascript
- Experienced in using editing software Photoshop, Adobe illustrator, Final Cut Pro X

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

My interests include photography, sketching, painting and front-end web development. I also enjoy listening to podcasts, crocheting and reading in my spare time. I like to keep myself physically fit and healthy and do so by regularly attending the gym and running.